Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Records Documenting Wrestling
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting wrestling
1919-1992
RU 944
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12.25
The records consist of correspondence, topical files, reports, scorecards, and scrapbooks, maintained by the Yale University Department of Athletics, documenting wrestling at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, topical files, reports, scorecards, and scrapbooks, maintained by the Yale University Department of Athletics, documenting wrestling at Yale.
Sensitive content in this finding aid has been redacted to prevent disclosure. Unredacted finding aid restricted to office of origin only.
College sports; Wrestling; Scrapbooks; Yale University Athletic Association; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Wrestling; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Scrapbooks of the wrestling team, 1919-1959; Accession 2006-A-016
  Scope and Contents
  Scrapbooks are available on microfilm. Patrons must use HM FILM 192 instead of the original scrapbooks.
  - Scrapbooks
    - Volume 1, 1919-1928 (Box 1, Reel 1, Box 2)
    - Volume 1, 1919-1928 (Box 2, Reel 1)
    - Volume 2, 1929-1931 (Box 3, Reel 1)
    - Volume 3, 1931-1938 (Box 4, Reel 2)
    - Volume 4, 1939-1959 (Box 5, Reel 2)
    - Volume 4, 1939-1959 (Box 6, Reel 2)
- Scorebooks of the wrestling team, circa 1933-1991; Accession 2006-A-022
  Arranged by topic, thereunder chronologically.
  - Records of wrestling meets
    - 1933-1938 (Box 1)
    - 1939 (Box 1)
  - Scorecards
    - 1944-1947, 1953-1955 (Box 1)
    - 1945-1957, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - 1958-1970 (Box 1)
  - Score books
    - 1932 (Box 1)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 1)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity; freshman, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
    - Freshman, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
    - Freshman, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
    - Freshman, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1958-1959 (Box 1)
    - Freshman, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
    - Freshman, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
    - Freshman, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
    - Frosh, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
    - Frosh, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - Frosh, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Frosh, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - A, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - B, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - A, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - B, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1978-1979 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Varsity, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Junior Varsity, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Varsity, 1981-1982 (Box 2)
    - Varsity, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
    - Junior Varsity
      - 1983-1984 (Box 2)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - Junior Varsity, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Junior Varsity, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
    - Varsity
      - 1985-1986 (Box 2)
      - 1987 (Box 2)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 2)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 2)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 2)
      - 1990-1991 (Box 2)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 2)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 2)
- Records of the wrestling team, 1927-1992; Accession 2006-A-107
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2027
  Arranged by topic.
  - Results and reports, 1927-1970, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 5)
  - Cancellation as varsity sport, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1992 (Box 1, Folder 7 - 10)
  - Eastern Intercollegiate Championships, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - EIWA Tournament programs, 1931-1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Financial records, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - NCAA, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Training schedule, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - [name redacted] grievance, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2067
    Other Finding Aids
    Unredacted PDF version of finding aid [office of origin only].
  - Publications, 1971-1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)